so really when we do relaxed consistency
we allow
reordering
of normal axises according to the four
types of ordering so for example our
reads can now be reordered but only if
these are normal accesses but then we
add special non-reorderable accesses
and the programmer must use these
non-reorderable accesses when ordering
in the program matters
an example of such non-reorderable
accesses is the x86 msync instruction
here
in normal execution all accesses are
reorderable
we cannot rely on any specific in-order
behavior as far as consistency is
concerned but no reordering can happen
across an msync instruction so we can
have
any accesses that we want reordered
anywhere in here but in program order
then comes the msync instruction the
processor guarantees that all of these
are going to be done before we do msync
and that the msync will be done before
we begin the next cloud of instructions
that can again be ordered with each
other so how does that help it helps
because now we can write flag
synchronization correctly the correct
weight for a flag now includes an msync
instruction it basically says that wait
for the flag to become zero
make that happen and then use the data
now the processor will first make sure
that the flag is red and only then that
the data is read
because we cannot reorder the reads to
the flag and data across nm sync but it
still allows all sorts of performance
optimizations
where we reorder instructions
in situations where we are not trying to
use memory for synchronization like this